To be honest, by personality,
说实话，从性格上来讲，
I'm just not much of a crier.
我并不是一个容易流泪的人。
But I think in my career that's been a good thing.
但考虑到我的职业， 能有这个性格是件好事。
I'm a civil rights lawyer,
我是一名民权律师，
and I've seen some  horrible things in the world.
我见过一些发生在 全球各地的可怕的事情。
I began my career working  police abuse cases in the United States.
我的第一份职业是在美国 处理警察滥用职权的案子。
And then in 1994, I was sent to Rwanda
后来，1994年，我被派往卢旺达，
to be the director of the U.N.'s  genocide investigation.
领导联合国种族灭绝调查组。
It turns out that tears  just aren't much help
我发现，当你调查 种族灭绝的惨案时，
when you're trying  to investigate a genocide.
泪水派不上多大用场。
The things I had to see,  and feel and touch
那些我不得不面对的事实， 那些令我感触深刻的故事，
were pretty unspeakable.
都难以名状。
What I can tell you is this:
我可以明确告诉你们的是：
that the Rwandan genocide
卢旺达种族灭绝是
was one of the world's greatest failures of simple compassion.
缺乏同情导致的 全世界最惨的惨案之一。
That word, compassion, actually  comes from two Latin words:
"同情"这个词 来源于两个拉丁词汇：
cum passio, which simply mean  "to suffer with."
cum和passio， 其含义是"同甘苦"。
And the things that I saw and experienced
目睹卢旺达的惨案，
in Rwanda as I got up close to human suffering,
我感受到了那里的 人们所承受的苦难，
it did, in moments, move me to tears.
这让我落下泪水。
But I just wish that I,  and the rest of the world,
我多么希望， 我，以及整个世界，
had been moved earlier.
可以在一切发生前就投以同情。
And not just to tears,
不单单是落下同情的泪水，
but to actually stop the genocide.
更要切实阻止这场惨案。
Now by contrast, I've also been involved
与之对比，我也经历了
with one of the world's greatest successes of compassion.
同情带来的最美好的硕果之一。
And that's the fight against  global poverty.
这就是全世界范围内 拯救贫困的运动。
It's a cause that probably has involved all of us here.
这场运动或许 跟在座的每个人都相关。
I don't know if your first introduction
我不知道是什么让 你们初次了解到世界贫困问题，
might have been choruses of "We Are the World,"
是"天下一家"这一合唱曲，
or maybe the picture of a sponsored child on your refrigerator door,
还是你们家冰箱门上贴着的 受到救济的儿童的照片，
or maybe the birthday you donated for fresh water.
还是你把过生日的钱拿去 捐给了水质净化项目？
I don't really remember what my first introduction to poverty was
我不记得是什么让我 第一次了解到贫困问题，
but I do remember the most jarring.
但我记得给我留下 最深刻印象的一次经历，
It was when I met Venus --
那一次我见到了Venus，
she's a mom from Zambia.
她是来自赞比亚的一位母亲，
She's got three kids and she's a widow.
她是一个遗孀，有三个孩子。
When I met her, she had walked about 12 miles
她走了大概12英里 才到了我们碰面的地方，
in the only garments she owned,
她穿着唯一的一套衣服，
to come to the capital city and to share her story.
来到首都，向我讲述她的故事。
She sat down with me for hours,
她坐着跟我聊了好几个小时，
just ushered me in to  the world of poverty.
让我深刻体会到了 贫穷世界究竟是何等模样。
She described what it was like  when the coals on the cooking fire
她向我描述着一幅幅贫困的画面：
finally just went completely cold.
煮食炉火的煤烧尽、凉透，
When that last drop  of cooking oil finally ran out.
最后一滴食用油消耗殆尽，
When the last of the food,  despite her best efforts,
尽管她极力节衣缩食，依然耗尽了
ran out.
最后一口食物。
She had to watch her youngest son, Peter,
她不得不眼睁睁地 看着小儿子 Peter
suffer from malnutrition,
遭受营养不良的折磨，
as his legs just slowly bowed  into uselessness.
他的双腿渐渐萎缩， 丧失了行走的能力。
As his eyes grew cloudy and dim.
他的眼睛变得黯淡无光，
And then as Peter finally grew cold.
直到最后，他的身子变冰冷了。
For over 50 years, stories like this have been moving us to compassion.
过去的五十多年间， 这样的故事激起了我们的同情心，
We whose kids have plenty to eat.
同情那些吃不饱饭的孩子。
And we're moved not only  to care about global poverty,
我们不只是在心里 默默关心全球贫困问题，
but to actually try to do our part  to stop the suffering.
还尽了自己的一份力， 让贫困的人不再受苦受难。
Now there's plenty of room for critique  that we haven't done enough,
有很多方面我们做的还不够，
and what it is that we've done hasn't been effective enough,
我们做的很多事情效果还不够显著，
but the truth is this:
但事实是：
The fight against global poverty is probably the broadest,
抗击世界贫困的运动很可能是
longest running manifestation of the  human phenomenon of compassion
人类出于同情心而发起的 有史以来涉及范围最广，
in the history of our species.
持续时间最为长久的运动。
And so I'd like to share a pretty shattering insight
我会给你们分享一些我的见解，
that might forever change the way you think about that struggle.
或许会永远改变大家 对这场运动的认识。
But first, let me begin with what you probably already know.
但首先，我来谈一下你们大多 已经知道的一些事实。
Thirty-five years ago, when I would have been graduating from high school,
35年前，我快要从高中毕业的时候，
they told us that 40,000 kids every day died because of poverty.
有数据表明每天有 四万个儿童死于饥饿。
That number, today, is now  down to 17,000.
今天，这个数字下降到一万七千。
Way too many, of course,
当然，还是很多，
but it does mean that every year,
但这确实表明，
there's eight million kids who don't have to die from poverty.
每年都有八百万名儿童 不会因饥饿而离开这个世界。
Moreover, the number of  people in our world
而且，全世界生活在
who are living in extreme poverty,
极度贫困状态的人数
which is defined as living off about a dollar and a quarter a day,
——极度贫困的定义是 每天用于糊口的钱不超过1.25美金——
that has fallen from 50 percent,
已经从世界人口的50%
to only 15 percent.
下降到只有15%。
This is massive progress,
这是卓越的进步，
and this exceeds everybody's  expectations about what is possible.
超出了所有人的预期。
And I think you and I,
我认为我们所有人，
I think, honestly, that we can  feel proud and encouraged
说实话， 我们应当为此而感到自豪，
to see the way that compassion  actually has the power
能够见证同情迸发出的力量
to succeed in stopping  the suffering of millions.
如何解救了数以百万计的人们。
But here's the part that you  might not hear very much about.
但后面这个数据 你们可能没听说过。
If you move that poverty mark just up to two dollars a day,
如果把贫困线稍稍上移， 设为一天2美金，
it turns out that virtually  the same two billion people
你就会发现世界上仍然有20亿人
who were stuck in that harsh poverty when I was in high school,
生活在极度贫困的状态下，
are still stuck there,
我上高中时有这么多人，
35 years later.
35年后的今天依然是。
So why, why are so many billions still stuck in such harsh poverty?
为什么呢？为什么有好几十亿人 深陷贫困的深渊？
Well, let's think about Venus for a moment.
让我们再回到Venus的故事。
Now for decades, my wife and I have been moved by common compassion
数十年来，我的夫人和我出于同情
to sponsor kids, to fund microloans,
帮助孩子，资助小额贷款，
to support generous levels of foreign aid.
慷慨地支持国外援救行动。
But until I had actually talked to Venus,
但直到我亲身跟Venus攀谈后，
I would have had no idea that  none of those approaches
我才知道以前所做的一切 都没有切中要害，
actually addressed why she had to watch her son die.
以致于她不得不眼睁睁地 看着她的孩子死去。
"We were doing fine," Venus told me,
“本来我们过得挺好，” Venus告诉我，
"until Brutus started to cause trouble."
”直到Brutus开始惹麻烦。“
Now, Brutus is Venus' neighbor  and "cause trouble"
Brutus是Venus的邻居， ”惹麻烦“是指
is what happened the day after Venus' husband died,
Venus丈夫去世后的第二天，
when Brutus just came and threw Venus and the kids out of the house,
Brutus将Venus 和她的孩子们赶出了家门，
stole all their land, and robbed their market stall.
掠去了所有的土地， 抢走了值钱的东西。
You see, Venus was thrown  into destitution by violence.
是暴力让Venus陷入贫困。
And then it occurred to me, of course,
这让我突然间意识到，
that none of my child sponsorships, none of the microloans,
我的儿童资助、小额贷款、
none of the traditional  anti-poverty programs
传统的抗击贫困的运动，
were going to stop Brutus,
都无法阻止Brutus，
because they weren't meant to.
因为所做的一切都没切中要害。
This became even more clear to me when I met Griselda.
当我遇到Griselda后， 我更加清晰地意识到这个问题。
She's a marvelous young girl living in a very poor community
她是一个美丽的年轻女子，
in Guatemala.
住在危地马拉 一个贫困不堪的社区。
And one of the things we've learned over the years
根据我们过去的经验，
is that perhaps the most powerful thing
我们认为让Griselda和她的家庭
that Griselda and her family can do
走出贫困的最有效的办法，
to get Griselda and her family  out of poverty
或许就是确保
is to make sure that she goes to school.
Griselda能够完成学业。
The experts call this the Girl Effect.
专家称之为“女孩效应”。
But when we met Griselda,  she wasn't going to school.
但当我们遇到Griselda时， 她并没有上学。
In fact, she was rarely ever  leaving her home.
事实上，她几乎走不出家门。
Days before we met her,
在我们遇见她的几天前，
while she was walking home from church with her family,
当她离开教堂， 跟家人走在回家的路上时，
in broad daylight,
光天化日之下，
men from her community  just snatched her off the street,
她所在社区的几个男人 把她从街道上拉走，
and violently raped her.
强暴了她。
See, Griselda had every opportunity to go to school,
所以，Griselda并不缺少上学的机会，
it just wasn't safe for her to get there.
只是上学的路上太不安全了。
And Griselda's not the only one.
Griselda并不是唯一 面临这个问题的孩子。
Around the world, poor women and girls
全世界，在15到44岁之间的
between the ages of 15 and 44,
贫困的妇女和女孩中，
they are -- when victims of  the everyday violence
因日常家庭暴力和性暴力侵犯
of domestic abuse and sexual violence --
而丧生或残疾的人数
those two forms of violence account for more death and disability
要超过因疟疾、交通事故、战争
than malaria, than car accidents, than war combined.
而死亡或残疾的妇女数量之和。
The truth is, the poor of our world are trapped in whole systems of violence.
真相是，全世界的穷人 都深陷暴力的牢笼。
In South Asia, for instance, I could drive past this rice mill
比如说，在南亚， 我开车驶过一片稻田，
and see this man hoisting  these 100-pound sacks
看到这个男人用他瘦弱的后背
of rice upon his thin back.
驼着100磅重的米袋。
But I would have no idea, until later,
但当时我根本就没想到，
that he was actually a slave,
他原来是一个奴隶，
held by violence in that rice mill since I was in high school.
在我上着高中时， 他就被迫碾米作坊劳作。
Decades of anti-poverty programs right in his community
数十年来，他所在社区的 抗击贫困的运动
were never able to rescue him or any of the hundred other slaves
都没能解救他， 也没能解救作坊中其他
from the beatings and the rapes and the torture
遭受殴打、强暴、酷刑的
of violence inside the rice mill.
百余名奴隶。
In fact, half a century of  anti-poverty programs
事实上，相对于 人类历史上其他任何时刻，
have left more poor people in slavery
近半世纪以来的抗击贫困的运动，
than in any other time in human history.
让人类历史上沦为奴隶的人数达到了顶峰。
Experts tell us that there's about 35 million people in slavery today.
专家告诉我们， 世界上目前大概有三千五百万奴隶。
That's about the population  of the entire nation of Canada,
这大概相当于加拿大 整个国家人口的数量，
where we're sitting today.
这就是目前的状况。
This is why, over time, I have come to call this epidemic of violence
这就是为什么， 我将这遍布的暴力称之为
the Locust Effect.
“蝗虫效应”。
Because in the lives of the poor, it just descends like a plague
因为，穷人们就像 遭受了一场瘟疫般，
and it destroys everything.
家庭支离破碎，生活惨不忍睹。
In fact, now when you survey very, very poor communities,
事实上，如今当你跟 那些极度贫困的社区居民交流时，
residents will tell you that their greatest fear is violence.
他们会告诉你 他们最大的恐惧，就是暴力。
But notice the violence that they fear
注意，他们恐惧的暴力
is not the violence of  genocide or the wars,
不是种族灭绝或战争，
it's everyday violence.
而是日常暴力。
So for me, as a lawyer, of course, my first reaction was to think,
因此，对我而言，作为一个律师， 我的第一个反应理所当然是，
well, of course we've got to change all the laws.
我们必须要修正法律。
We've got to make all this violence against the poor illegal.
我们必须以法律作为武器 严惩暴力行为。
But then I found out, it already is.
但我随即发现， 相关法律条文已经有了。
The problem is not that  the poor don't get laws,
问题不在于 没有保护穷人的法律条文，
it's that they don't get law enforcement.
而在于法律得不到实施。
In the developing world,
在发展中国家，
basic law enforcement systems are so broken
践行法律的机构系统腐朽不堪，
that recently the U.N. issued  a report that found
联合国最近的报告显示，
that "most poor people live outside the protection of the law."
”绝大多数穷人 得不到法律保障。“
Now honestly, you and I have  just about no idea
说实话，你我都想象不到，
of what that would mean
没有法律保障意味着什么，
because we have no  first-hand experience of it.
因为我们都没有切身体会过。
Functioning law enforcement for us  is just a total assumption.
在我们心目中， 法律的践行完全是理所当然的，
In fact, nothing expresses that assumption more clearly than three simple numbers:
事实上，给我们吃定心丸的 就是那三个数字：
9-1-1,
911，
which, of course, is the number for the emergency police operator
不用说，这就是加拿大和美国
here in Canada and in the United States,
通用的紧急报警号码，
where the average response time  to a police 911 emergency call
拨打911的警方平均响应时间
is about 10 minutes.
大概是10分钟。
So we take this just  completely for granted.
我们认为这完全是理所当然的。
But what if there was no  law enforcement to protect you?
但是，如果没有法律保护你， 会发生什么？
A woman in Oregon recently experienced what this would be like.
俄勒冈州的一名女子 最近就有过这样的切身经历。
She was home alone in her  dark house on a Saturday night,
在一个周六的夜晚， 她独自呆在灯光昏暗的家中，
when a man started to tear  his way into her home.
此时一名男子试图撬门而入。
This was her worst nightmare,
这是她一段噩梦般的经历，
because this man had actually put her in the hospital from an assault
因为就在两周前， 这个男子袭击了她，
just two weeks before.
让她受伤住进了医院。
So terrified, she picks up that phone and does what any of us would do:
惊慌失措中，她拿起电话， 像所有人都会做的那样：
She calls 911 --
她拨打了911——
but only to learn that because  of budget cuts in her county,
但却发现她所在的郡县为节约资金，
law enforcement wasn't available  on the weekends.
周末并不提供警力援助。
Listen.
请听。
Dispatcher: I don't have anybody  to send out there.
话务员：这边没有人可以过去。
Woman: OK
女子：好吧。
Dispatcher: Um, obviously if he comes inside the residence and assaults you,
话务员：嗯， 如果他要闯入你家侵犯你，
can you ask him to go away?
你能跟他说，让他走吗？
Or do you know if he is intoxicated or anything?
或者，你知道他是不是 喝醉了之类的吗？
Woman: I've already asked him. I've already told him I was calling you.
女子：我已经跟他说不要进来了。 我已经告诉他我拨911了。
He's broken in before, busted down my door, assaulted me.
以前他就闯入过我家，侵犯了我。
Dispatcher: Uh-huh.
话务员：呃，嗯。
Woman: Um, yeah, so ...
女子：呃，这样，那么......
Dispatcher: Is there any way you could safely leave the residence?
话务员：你有没有办法 安全地逃出家门？
Woman: No, I can't, because he's blocking pretty much my only way out.
女子：没有，没办法， 因为他堵在我唯一的出口。
Dispatcher: Well, the only thing I can do  is give you some advice,
话务员：好吧，我唯一能做的 就是给你一些建议，
and call the sheriff's office tomorrow.
明天我会报告给警官。
Obviously, if he comes in and unfortunately has a weapon
当然，如果他闯进来，还拿着武器，
or is trying to cause you physical harm, that's a different story.
或试图给你造成身体伤害， 那就是另一回事了。
You know, the sheriff's office doesn't work up there.
你也知道，警局今天休息，
I don't have anybody to send."
我没法派人去救你。“
Gary Haugen: Tragically, the woman  inside that house
不幸的是，这名女子在自己家里
was violently assaulted, choked and raped
被残暴地殴打，窒息，强奸，
because this is what it means to live outside the rule of law.
这就是生活在法律保障之外的情形。
And this is where billions of our poorest live.
这就是数十亿穷人所生活的环境。
What does that look like?
具体是什么样的呢？
In Bolivia, for example, if a man  sexually assaults a poor child,
比如，在玻利维亚，如果一个男人 对一个穷人家的孩子性骚扰，
statistically, he's at greater risk of slipping in the shower and dying
从统计数字来看，他被逮捕的概率
than he is of ever going  to jail for that crime.
还没有洗澡跌倒致死的概率高。
In South Asia, if you  enslave a poor person,
在南非，如果你奴役一个穷人，
you're at greater risk of being  struck by lightning
你更可能遭到雷劈，
than ever being sent  to jail for that crime.
而不是被逮捕。
And so the epidemic of everyday  violence, it just rages on.
日常暴力如瘟疫般席卷着穷人的世界。
And it devastates our efforts to try to help billions of people
这让我们为帮助 数十亿穷人脱离贫困线
out of their two-dollar-a-day hell.
所付出的一切努力化为泡影。
Because the data just doesn't lie.
因为数据不会说谎。
It turns out that you can give  all manner of goods and services
你可以倾尽所有，为穷人提供
to the poor,
救济品和服务设施，
but if you don't restrain the hands  of the violent bullies
但如果你不遏制抢走
from taking it all away,
这一切的暴徒，
you're going to be very disappointed in the long-term impact of your efforts.
你所付出的努力会让你失望透顶。
So you would think that the disintegration of basic law enforcement
因此，你们会觉得抗击 全球贫困的头等要事
in the developing world would be a huge priority
是解决发展中国家最基本的
for the global fight against poverty.
法律实施问题。
But it's not.
但并不是这样的。
Auditors of international assistance recently couldn't find
国际援助的审查者发现，
even one percent of aid going  to protect the poor
穷人的援助金中，
from the lawless chaos  of everyday violence.
用在帮助穷人逃脱暴力方面的部分 连百分之一都不到。
And honestly, when we do talk about  violence against the poor,
当我们谈论穷人面对的暴力问题时，
sometimes it's in the weirdest of ways.
状况却奇怪得让人匪夷所思。
A fresh water organization tells a heart-wrenching story
一个纯净水援助组织 先是讲述了一个揪心的故事，
of girls who are raped on the way to fetching water,
女孩们在打水的路上遭到强暴，
and then celebrates the solution of a new well
然后便为在她们家附近修建了水井，
that drastically shortens their walk.
解决了她们长途取水的问题 而沾沾自喜。
End of story.
一切就这样到此为止了。
But not a word about the rapists who are still right there in the community.
压根儿就没有提到 活跃在她们社区的暴力分子。
If a young woman on one  of our college campuses
如果我们这有一个女大学生
was raped on her walk to the library,
在去图书馆的路上遭人强暴，
we would never celebrate the solution of moving the library closer to the dorm.
我们绝对不会赞扬 将图书馆移到宿舍附近的解决办法。
And yet, for some reason, this is okay for poor people.
但是出于某种原因，对于穷人而言， 这种办法却是可行的。
Now the truth is, the traditional experts
事实上，
in economic development and poverty alleviation,
传统的发展经济和抗击贫困的专家
they don't know how to fix this problem.
并不知道如何解决这个问题。
And so what happens?
那要怎么办呢？
They don't talk about it.
他们只好对此保持沉默。
But the more fundamental reason
但发展中国家的穷人
that law enforcement for the poor in the developing world
得不到法律援助的现状 如此遭人冷落，
is so neglected,
其更深层次的原因在于，
is because the people inside the developing world, with money,
发展中国家的富人们
don't need it.
根本不需要法律援助。
I was at the World Economic  Forum not long ago
不久之前，在一个世界经济论坛上，
talking to corporate executives who have massive businesses in the developing world
我与几位跟发展中国家 有广泛商业往来的高管们交谈，
and I was just asking them,
我问他们，
"How do you guys protect all your people and property from all the violence?"
“你们这些人怎么 保护家人和财产不受侵害？”
And they looked at each other,  and they said, practically in unison,
他们面面相觑，几乎异口同声地说，
"We buy it."
“我们拿钱买保障。”
Indeed, private security forces  in the developing world
事实上，发展中国家私人保卫力量
are now, four, five and seven times larger than the public police force.
是公共警力的 五倍、六倍，甚至八倍。
In Africa, the largest employer  on the continent now is private security.
在非洲这片大陆上， 目前最大的生意就是私人警卫。
But see, the rich can pay for safety and can keep getting richer,
富人可以用金钱买来安全， 并能不断积累财富，
but the poor can't pay for it and they're left totally unprotected
但穷人买不起， 只能深陷在危险的环境中，
and they keep getting thrown to the ground.
这种情况愈演愈烈。
This is a massive and scandalous outrage.
这种无处不在的丑闻 简直让我怒不可遏。
And it doesn't have to be this way.
事实完全不必这样发展下去。
Broken law enforcement can be fixed.
腐朽的法律实施系统可以修复。
Violence can be stopped.
暴力可以被停止。
Almost all criminal justice systems,
几乎所有惩治罪犯的系统，
they start out broken and corrupt,
起初都难免会有漏洞和腐败，
but they can be transformed by fierce effort and commitment.
但不懈的努力和坚定的决心 可以让系统走向完善。
The path forward is really pretty clear.
前方要走的路非常清晰。
Number one: We have to start making
第一，我们必须让抗击暴力
stopping violence indispensable  to the fight against poverty.
成为抗击贫困斗争中 不可缺少的一部分。
In fact, any conversation about global poverty
事实上，如果在谈论贫困时
that doesn't include the problem  of violence must be deemed not serious.
不涉及暴力问题， 那必然就没有抓住问题的实质。
And secondly, we have to begin  to seriously invest resources
其次，我们必须大力
and share expertise to support  the developing world
提供资源和专家援助，
as they fashion new,  public systems of justice,
为发展中国家建立新的公共保障系统，
not private security,
而不是私人保卫，
that give everybody a chance to be safe.
这样才会尽可能保障每个人的安全。
These transformations  are actually possible
这种转变是切实可行的，
and they're happening today.
并且已经在进行中了。
Recently, the Gates Foundation  funded a project
最近，盖茨基金会资助了
in the second largest city  of the Philippines,
在菲律宾第二大城市的一个项目，
where local advocates and local law enforcement
当地的积极分子和法律工作者
were able to transform corrupt police and broken courts so drastically,
成功地改革了腐败的执法系统和 不作为的法院，
that in just four short years,
在短短的四年间，
they were able to measurably reduce
针对贫穷儿童的
the commercial sexual violence  against poor kids by 79 percent.
性暴力事件就有效地减少了79%。
You know, from the hindsight of history,
有了前车之鉴，
what's always most inexplicable and inexcusable
最说不过去、最令人无法容忍的事实
are the simple failures of compassion.
就是同情心的丧失。
Because I think history convenes  a tribunal of our grandchildren
因为，历史之镜会照出我们的良心，
and they just ask us,
我们的子孙后代会质问我们，
"Grandma, Grandpa, where were you?
“爷爷奶奶，你们那时在干什么？
Where were you, Grandpa, when  the Jews were fleeing Nazi Germany
爷爷，当犹太人逃离纳粹德国，
and were being rejected from our shores?
却在我们的海岸线遭到拒绝时，
Where were you?
您在哪儿？
And Grandma, where were you when they were marching
奶奶，当他们践踏日裔美国人，
our Japanese-American neighbors off to internment camps?
将他们关押起来时，您在哪儿？
And Grandpa, where were you  when they were beating
爷爷，当那些非洲裔美国人
our African-American neighbors
只是因为想要获得投票权
just because they were trying to register to vote?"
而遭到殴打时，您在哪儿？”
Likewise, when our grandchildren ask us,
诸如此类，当我们的孙辈问我们，
"Grandma, Grandpa, where were you
“爷爷，奶奶，
when two billion of the world's poorest were drowning in a lawless chaos
当世界上最穷的二十亿人遭受日常暴力 却得不到法律保障时，
of everyday violence?"
您在哪儿？”
I hope we can say that we had compassion, that we raised our voice,
我希望我们可以回答说： 我们赋予了同情心、发出了呼吁，
and as a generation, we were moved to make the violence stop.
我们这一代人都为之动容， 也尽力去制止了暴力行为。
Thank you very much.
非常感谢。
(Applause)
（掌声）
Chris Anderson: Really powerfully argued.
Chris Anderson:  这真是个震撼人心的演讲。
Talk to us a bit about some of the things
告诉我们一些
that have actually been happening to, for example, boost police training.
正在开展的行动吧， 比如，警力的训练。
How hard a process is that?
这样的过程有多难？
GH: Well, one of the glorious  things that's starting to happen now
GH: 现在正在进行的 最令人赞叹的事情之一就是
is that the collapse of these systems and the consequences are becoming obvious.
这些体系的坍塌及其 后果已浮出水面，
There's actually, now,  political will to do that.
政客们正着力解决。
But it just requires now an investment of resources and transfer of expertise.
但现在正需要资源和专业技能的投入。
There's a political will struggle  that's going to take place as well,
政治上也会有些阻力，
but those are winnable fights,
但这些都是可以解决的，
because we've done some examples around the world
因为全世界范围内已有先例，
at International Justice Mission that are very encouraging.
比如“国际正义行动”就很鼓舞人心。
CA: So just tell us in one country, how much it costs
CA: 告诉我们，在一个国家，
to make a material difference  to police, for example --
比如，要彻底革新警力系统， 需要多少投入——
I know that's only one piece of it.
我知道这只是其中一小部分。
GH: In Guatemala, for instance, we've started a project there
GH: 比如在危地马拉， 我们开展了一项运动，
with the local police  and court system, prosecutors,
训练当地的警力、司法系统和检察官，
to retrain them so that they can  actually effectively bring these cases.
提升他们的执行能力， 以有效地将罪犯绳之以法。
And we've seen prosecutions against perpetrators of sexual violence
我们已经得知， 此后对性暴力罪犯的诉讼
increase by more than 1,000 percent.
增加了十倍之多。
This project has been very modestly funded at about a million dollars a year,
这项运动所需的资金 大概是每年一百万美金，
and the kind of bang  you can get for your buck
从中得到的丰硕的回报就是，
in terms of leveraging a criminal justice system
如果可以训练出一只强大的队伍， 激励并有效地引领他们，
that could function if it were properly trained and motivated and led,
打击罪犯、维护正义的体系 就可以高效地运作起来，
and these countries,  especially a middle class
在这些国家，尤其是中产阶层
that is seeing that there's  really no future
过去看到这不安定的局势、
with this total instability and total privatization of security
完全私人化的警力时是多么无助，
I think there's an opportunity, a window for change.
但我认为现在已经有了 去改变这一现状的机会了。
CA: But to make this happen, you have to look at each part in the chain --
CA: 要让这成为现实， 你需要关注整条链上的每一个环节——
the police, who else?
警方，还有呢？
GH: So that's the thing  about law enforcement,
GH: 关于法律的实施，
it starts out with the police,
从警方开始，
they're the front end of the pipeline of justice,
他们维护正义，奋斗在前线，
but they hand if off to the prosecutors,
他们将罪犯送到检察官手里，
and the prosecutors  hand it off to the courts,
检察官再将罪犯送上法庭，
and the survivors of violence  have to be supported by social services
惨遭暴力的幸存者始终都需要
all the way through that.
得到社会的保障与支持。
So you have to do an approach  that pulls that all together.
所以你需要做的就是 把这几方面结合在一起。
In the past, there's been a little bit of training of the courts,
过去，对法院的培训很少，
but they get crappy evidence  from the police,
法院只能从警方得到蹩脚的证据，
or a little police intervention  that has to do with narcotics or terrorism
姑且不说这对惩治毒贩 和恐怖分子有多少帮助，
but nothing to do with treating the common poor person
他们在建立完善的法律实施体系来
with excellent law enforcement,
保障广大穷人的利益方面 几乎没有任何作为，
so it's about pulling that all together,
因此，我们需要把 每一个环节有机地结合起来，
and you can actually have people in very poor communities
让那些生活在贫困中的人们
experience law enforcement like us,
像我们一样 得到法律的切实保障，
which is imperfect in our  own experience, for sure,
或许我们还对身边的问题满腹牢骚，
but boy, is it a great thing to sense that you can call 911
但是当你知道只要拨打911，
and maybe someone will protect you.
就会有人来保护你了， 是多么的不容易。
CA: Gary, I think you've done  a spectacular job
CA: Gary, 你太了不起了，
of bringing this to the world's attention
通过你的书还有今天的演讲，
in your book and right here today.
你会让全世界都开始关注这个问题。
Thanks so much.
非常感谢，
Gary Haugen.
Gary Haugen。
(Applause)
（掌声）